# Mohamed Ramadan

## Junior Site Engineer

Zahraa Nasr City, Cairo, Egypt +201555531293 mohmd.ramadan1993@gmail.com Military Status: Completed

### Skills

- Presentation Skills
- Communication Skills
- Team Leading
- Working under Stress
- Perfection Seeker

## Courses

### Construction Design

**Creative Group** 

## Core Skills :

- Safe
- SAP
- ETABS
- AutoCaD
- ICDL

## Languages

- Arabic (Mother Tongue)
- English (Excellent)
- German (Beginner)

## Social Accounts

in LinkedIn Account @mohamed-ramadan-118906120 Junior Engineer with 5 years of experience in construction field who played a significant role in two mega projects (Cairo Monorail east line, and New Administrative Capital ministries).

Also smoothly handled a subcontractor role at New Administrative R5 residential project.

Brightly started career with construction of New Administrative fence of knowledge city followed by SI project at the ministries avenue.

# Experience

### Site Engineer | Orascom Construction | July 2021 - Present

Responsible for line piles, steel formwork for columns, stations foundation, structure elements, steel structures and finishing, precast beams manufacturing, lifting of precast beams at Monorail project

Sub-contractor | Alexandria for Construction | Dec 2020 – July 2021 Responsible for walls, ceilings and facades finish in R5 cluster 7 at The New Administrative Capital

Site Engineer | Alexandria for Construction | June 2020 – Dec 2020 Responsible for concrete, landscape and finishing at SI project New Administrative Capital Ministries' Avenue

Site Engineer | Alexandria for Construction | Jan 2020 – June 2020 Site Engineer at Knowledge city at The New Administrative Capital

Site Engineer | Alexandria for Construction | July 2019 – Jan 2020 Responsible for basement walls, ceiling and floor finishing at Petroleum Ministry New Administrative Capital Ministries' Avenue

### Intern | Alexandria for Construction | June 2017

Responsible for concrete floors and upstands at Petroleum Ministry New Administrative Capital

#### Intern | Arab Contractors | June 2016

Summer Internship for 3 months at Arab Contractors headquarter.

#### Intern | Alexandria for Construction | July 2015

Summer Internship for one month at Al Rehab club extensions

## Education

#### Ain Shams University - Credit Hours Program

Bachelor of Engineering | Building Engineering | Jan 2018 Project's Grade: Excellent

High School | MOAI Experimental language School.

Grade: 96.5%